Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we're bringing you the eighth part of our dramatic romantic love story, I'm sorry
今天我们带来的是我们浪漫爱情故事戏剧性的第八部分，剧名是《对不起》。
I love you.
《我爱你》。
That's right, we're coming close to the end of this story, aren't we?
没错，我们快接近这个故事的结尾了，对吧？
Yeah, we're coming close to the end and we still have a lot of interesting things going
是啊，我们快接近结尾了，还有很多有趣的事情在发生。
on so I wonder what's going to happen.
所以我很想知道接下来会发生什么。
Well, I can tell you that today's lesson involves this word which we'll hear in vocabulary preview.
嗯，我可以告诉你今天的课程涉及一个词，我们会在词汇预览中听到。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
So today we're just going to look at this one word, spy.
所以今天我们只看一个词：间谍。
A spy.
间谍。
Spy.
Alright, so we probably know famous spies like James Bond.
好，我们可能知道像詹姆斯·邦德这样的著名间谍。
Or Austin Powers.
或者奥斯汀·鲍尔斯。
Right.
对。
So basically it's a person who is secretly trying to get information.
所以基本上，这是一个秘密试图获取信息的人。
About a government or maybe a business.
关于政府或可能的企业。
Right.
对。
So that's a spy.
那就是间谍。
Now the verb, to spy.
现在动词是“监视”。
Same thing, right?
一样，对吧？
To spy on someone.
监视某人。
To spy on a company.
监视一家公司。
So why are we talking spies and spying here on EnglishPod?
那我们为什么在EnglishPod上谈论间谍和监视呢？
Why don't we find out by listening to our dialogue.
我们不如通过听对话来找出答案。
Hi Steven.
嗨，Steven。
I haven't been completely honest with you, Veronica. I'm sorry. I'm not a fireman. I'm not even from the United States. I'm a spy for the Indian government.
我一直没有完全对你诚实，Veronica。对不起。我不是消防员。我甚至不是美国人。我是印度政府的间谍。
What? Why didn't you tell me before? What are you doing here?
什么？你之前为什么不告诉我？你在这里做什么？
When I was a young boy, I used to play cricket with my father back in my hometown of Hyderabad.
我小时候，常和我父亲在我的家乡海得拉巴打板球。
It was a peaceful town, and my father was a renowned chemist. One day he was approached by members of the CIA, claiming that my father had made the discovery of the Millennium in his small lab back at the university, where he taught biochemistry.
那是一个宁静的小镇，我父亲是一位著名的化学家。有一天，中情局的人找到他，声称我父亲在他教生物化学的大学小实验室里做出了千禧年的发现。
I never saw him again. I vowed to discover the whereabouts of my father, and consequently joined the Indian Intelligence Bureau.
我再也没见过他。我发誓要找到我父亲的下落，于是加入了印度情报局。
What does that have to do with those men shooting at us? And most importantly, why did you lie to me?
那和那些朝我们开枪的人有什么关系？最重要的是，你为什么对我撒谎？
I'm sorry. I wasn't supposed to meet you. I wasn't supposed to fall in love with you. But you have to believe me when I tell you that what I feel for you is real.
对不起。我不该遇见你。我不该爱上你。但你必须相信我，我对你的感情是真的。
I can't believe this. Why are all these things happening to me? I can't take it anymore. Let me out of the car.
我无法相信。为什么所有这些事都发生在我身上？我受不了了。让我下车。
Veronica, wait!
Veronica，等等！
Alright, so Stephen is not even American. He's an Indian spy.
好，所以Stephen甚至不是美国人。他是印度间谍。
He's not even a firefighter.
他甚至不是消防员。
Well, there you go.
好吧，就是这样。
Oh my God.
哦，天哪。
Many surprises on this love story.
这个爱情故事有很多惊喜。
It gets deeper and deeper.
越来越深了。
Well, why don't we take a look at some of the vocabulary that was used in this great story in Language Takeaway.
嗯，我们不如在“语言要点”中看看这个故事里用到的一些词汇。
Language Takeaway
语言要点
Well, here we've got a lot of language that you can use when you need to be honest about something.
嗯，这里有很多语言，当你需要对某事诚实的时候可以用。
We're going to look at six phrases here. Now, the first one, Stephen says he needs to come clean.
我们要看六个短语。第一个，Stephen说他需要坦白。
Come clean.
坦白。
Right, so basically he needs to tell the truth.
对，所以基本上他需要说出真相。
He needs to confess.
他需要忏悔。
Confess, right.
忏悔，对。
About something that he maybe wasn't truthful about in the past.
关于他过去可能不诚实的事情。
Yeah, maybe he had a secret or maybe he lied about something.
是啊，也许他有个秘密，或者他撒了谎。
Yep.
是的。
So, now he's coming clean.
所以，他现在在坦白。
Very good.
很好。
So, he comes clean and he tells the story about his childhood and he says his father was a renowned chemist.
所以他坦白了，讲述了他童年的故事，说他父亲是一位著名的化学家。
Renowned.
著名的。
Okay, so if you're a renowned chemist.
好，如果你是一位著名的化学家。
You're very famous and well respected.
你非常有名且备受尊敬。
So, you can use that with people or with places.
所以你可以用它来形容人或地方。
A renowned restaurant.
一家著名的餐厅。
Okay, so very popular, very well known.
好，所以非常受欢迎，非常有名。
We also hear it commonly like this, a world renowned chemist.
我们也常听到这样的说法：世界著名的化学家。
A world renowned restaurant.
世界著名的餐厅。
So, not only popular locally, but the whole world knows about it.
所以不仅在本地受欢迎，全世界都知道。
Very good.
很好。
Alright, and so he continues with his story and he says he was approached by members of the CIA.
好，他继续讲他的故事，他说中情局的人找上了他。
Approached.
找上。
To be approached by.
被……找上。
Okay, so if I am approached by somebody from the CIA, what does that mean?
好，如果中情局的人找上我，那是什么意思？
Well, they come to talk to you about something really important.
嗯，他们来找你谈非常重要的事。
Okay, so the verb to approach someone can mean get close to.
好，所以动词“approach”可以表示靠近。
Right, to walk up to them or something like that.
对，走向他们之类的。
Right, but it also carries this meaning of coming to talk to you about something.
对，但它也有来找你谈某事的意思。
Something important.
重要的事。
Something very important.
非常重要的事。
Yep.
是的。
So, for example, I can say my boss approached me this morning to talk about an important pay raise.
所以，比如，我可以说我老板今天早上找了我，谈重要的加薪。
Oh, lucky you. Or maybe Jim approached me to ask if I know if his wife is cheating on him or not.
哦，你真幸运。或者Jim找了我，问我是否知道他妻子有没有出轨。
Wow. Alright, so that's how you would use this verb, approach someone.
哇。好，这就是你如何使用这个动词“approach someone”。
Now, let's move on to the next word.
现在，我们来看下一个词。
So, he was approached by members of the CIA and they were claiming something about his father.
所以中情局的人找上了他，他们声称关于他父亲的一些事。
That's right. So, to claim.
没错。所以是“声称”。
Claim something.
声称某事。
To claim something.
Alright, so basically when you're claiming something, you are saying that it's true.
好，基本上当你声称某事时，你在说它是真的。
Right, it might not be true.
对，可能不是真的。
But we don't know.
但我们不知道。
Yep. So, for example, he claims he makes $4 million a year.
是的。所以，比如，他声称他一年赚400万美元。
Okay, or Bob claims that he saw a UFO.
好，或者Bob声称他看到了UFO。
We can't prove it if it's true or not, but that's what they're saying is true.
我们无法证明是真是假，但那是他们说的真话。
Yep.
是的。
So, Stephen's father disappeared and, well, he vowed to discover where he was.
所以Stephen的父亲失踪了，他发誓要找到他在哪里。
So, Stephen vowed to find his father.
所以Stephen发誓要找到他的父亲。
Vow.
发誓。
To vow.
So, this verb, to vow, means to make a strong promise, right?
所以这个动词“vow”意思是做出一个强烈的承诺，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
And we use it also in marriage, right?
我们在婚姻中也用它，对吧？
Wedding vows.
婚礼誓言。
Wedding vows, which are basically promises.
婚礼誓言，基本上就是承诺。
So, if you vow something, you make a very strong promise.
所以如果你发誓某事，你做出了一个非常强烈的承诺。
Yes, it's very, very bad if you break a vow.
是的，如果你违背誓言，那非常非常糟糕。
Oh, really? What happens?
哦，真的吗？会发生什么？
I don't know, probably thunder strikes you and you die.
我不知道，可能雷劈你，然后你死了。
Alright, so don't break your vows.
好，所以不要违背你的誓言。
And the last word on Language Takeaway today, the whereabouts.
今天“语言要点”的最后一个词是“下落”。
The whereabouts.
下落。
The whereabouts of his father.
他父亲的下落。
So, the whereabouts is the location.
所以“下落”就是位置。
The location.
位置。
Kind of unknown location, right?
有点未知的位置，对吧？
Right. I think this is a great word for us to listen to some more examples.
对。我觉得这个词很好，我们来听更多例子。
Example 1.
例子1。
The police don't have any information on the whereabouts of the murderer.
警方没有关于凶手下落的任何信息。
Example 2.
例子2。
Currently, the whereabouts of the president are unknown.
目前，总统的下落不明。
Example 3.
例子3。
You live in Toronto too? Whereabouts do you live?
你也住在多伦多？你住在哪里？
Alright, so whereabouts. Perfect.
好，所以“whereabouts”。完美。
You can use it for location, unknown location.
你可以用它来表示位置，未知位置。
Alright, so some great words.
好，一些很棒的词。
Now, I want to move on to some phrases that we use a lot in the US.
现在，我想继续讲一些我们在美国常用的短语。
Some great words. Now, I want to move on to some phrases that we heard in the dialogue.
一些很棒的词。现在，我想继续讲一些我们在对话中听到的短语。
And let's look at those now in Fluency Builder.
让我们在“流利度构建”中看看这些。
Alright, on Fluency Builder today, we have four great phrases.
好，今天的“流利度构建”有四个很棒的短语。
And let's start with the first one.
我们从第一个开始。
So, Veronica asks, what's going on?
所以Veronica问：“发生什么事了？”
Basically, what's happening, right?
基本上就是“发生了什么”，对吧？
What's happening, what's the situation?
发生了什么，情况怎么样？
Now, another interesting thing is that among friends, you could use this phrase to say,
另一个有趣的是，在朋友之间，你可以用这个短语来打招呼。
Hey, how are you? How's it going?
嘿，你好吗？怎么样？
So, you can say, hey, Erica, what's going on?
所以你可以说，嘿，Erica，发生什么事了？
And it all depends on your tone of voice.
这完全取决于你的语气。
So, when you want to know how that person is, hey, Marco, what's going on?
所以当你想知道那个人怎么样时，嘿，Marco，发生什么事了？
Right, but if you're angry or maybe something strange is happening, you're like, hey, what's going on here?
对，但如果你生气或有什么奇怪的事发生，你会说，嘿，这里发生什么事了？
Yes, so your voice falls.
是的，所以你的语调会下降。
Right, now let's take a look at our next phrase. And this one is very, very useful, especially if you've lied.
对，现在来看下一个短语。这个非常非常有用，特别是如果你撒了谎。
Yes, so Stephen says, I haven't been completely honest with you.
是的，所以Stephen说：“我一直没有完全对你诚实。”
I haven't been completely honest with you.
我一直没有完全对你诚实。
So, that means he hasn't been telling the whole truth.
所以那意味着他没有说出全部真相。
Right, pretty easy to understand, but I think its use is interesting here.
对，很容易理解，但我认为它的用法在这里很有趣。
Right, you might use it to kind of soften up the person to confess something.
对，你可能会用它来缓和气氛，以便坦白某事。
Right, so when you're ready to come clean about a secret you have or a lie you told, this is a great way to prepare your listener.
对，所以当你准备坦白一个秘密或你撒的谎时，这是让听者做好准备的好方法。
Right, you know what? I haven't been completely honest with you.
对，你知道吗？我一直没有完全对你诚实。
Moving on to our third phrase.
继续到我们的第三个短语。
So, the CIA claimed that Stephen's father had made the discovery of the millennium.
所以中情局声称Stephen的父亲做出了千禧年的发现。
The discovery of the millennium.
千禧年的发现。
Discovery of the millennium.
Okay, let's break this down. Millennium.
好，我们来分解一下。千禧年。
Millennium is a thousand years.
千禧年是一千年。
Right.
对。
So, the discovery of the millennium is...
所以千禧年的发现是……
The best, most important discovery in the past thousand years.
过去一千年里最好、最重要的发现。
Right, so now we can change it a little bit and say the invention of the millennium.
对，所以我们可以稍微改一下，说千禧年的发明。
Or even the party of the millennium.
甚至千禧年的派对。
Exactly, so it doesn't necessarily have to be the most important of the last one thousand years.
没错，所以不一定非得是过去一千年里最重要的。
But it means it was pretty good.
但意思是它相当不错。
It was pretty good or very important.
相当不错或非常重要。
Hey, you can also say the discovery of the decade, right?
嘿，你也可以说十年的发现，对吧？
Of the decade, of the century, of the year.
十年的、世纪的、年度的。
And now let's take a look at our last phrase.
现在来看最后一个短语。
So, Stephen confessed he came clean, he told her everything, but he said he wasn't supposed to fall in love with her.
所以Stephen坦白了，他告诉了她一切，但他说他不该爱上她。
I wasn't supposed to.
我不该。
I wasn't supposed to fall in love with you.
我不该爱上你。
Alright, so let's look at this phrase, I wasn't supposed to.
好，我们来看这个短语“我不该”。
It's an interesting one, it's sort of like a cross between I didn't need to and I shouldn't have done.
这是一个有趣的短语，有点像“我不需要”和“我不应该做”的结合。
Right, now let's look at some examples.
对，现在来看一些例子。
I wasn't supposed to come to work today.
我今天不该来上班。
Alright, so you didn't need to.
好，所以你不需要。
It wasn't necessary.
没有必要。
Alright, so maybe it was your annual vacation day but you came into work anyway.
好，所以也许是你年假的日子，但你还是来上班了。
Or maybe it was a holiday and I came to work anyways.
或者也许是假日，我还是来上班了。
So, the plan was not for you to come to work.
所以计划不是让你来上班。
Right, so in this case we're saying it wasn't necessary.
对，所以在这种情况下，我们说没有必要。
Or it wasn't planned.
或者没有计划。
Or planned.
或者计划。
Now let's look at it the other way, when you shouldn't.
现在来看另一种情况，当你不应该时。
Okay, Marco I wasn't supposed to tell you this but...
好，Marco，我不该告诉你这个，但是……
Okay, so now in this case you shouldn't be telling me this, you shouldn't tell me the secret, but you're going to anyways.
好，所以在这种情况下，你不应该告诉我这个，你不应该告诉我秘密，但你还是要说。
Yes, off air.
是的，下播后。
So, I wasn't supposed to, in this case it means I shouldn't.
所以“我不该”，在这种情况下意思是“我不应该”。
Alright, some really great language here, now I think it would help us to hear it one more time in the dialogue.
好，一些非常棒的语言，现在我想再听一遍对话会有帮助。
Veronica, Veronica, Veronica, are you okay?
Veronica，Veronica，Veronica，你还好吗？
Steven, what's going on? Who were those guys?
Steven，发生什么事了？那些人是谁？
I didn't know you have a gun. What's going on?
我不知道你有枪。发生什么事了？
I will come clean as soon as we get to safety, okay?
我们一到安全的地方我就坦白，好吗？
For now you have to trust me, please, I would never do anything to hurt you.
现在你必须相信我，求你了，我绝不会做任何伤害你的事。
Steven, I...
Steven，我……
Okay, run!
好，快跑！
I haven't been completely honest with you, Veronica, I'm sorry.
我一直没有完全对你诚实，Veronica，对不起。
I'm not a fireman, I'm not even from the United States.
我不是消防员，我甚至不是美国人。
I'm a spy for the Indian government.
我是印度政府的间谍。
What? Why didn't you tell me before? What are you doing here?
什么？你之前为什么不告诉我？你在这里做什么？
When I was a young boy, I used to play cricket with my father back in my hometown of Hyderabad.
我小时候，常和我父亲在我的家乡海得拉巴打板球。
It was a peaceful town, and my father was a renowned chemist.
那是一个宁静的小镇，我父亲是一位著名的化学家。
One day he was approached by members of the CIA, claiming that my father had made the discovery of the Millennium in his small lab back at the university, where he taught biochemistry.
有一天，中央情报局的人找到他，声称我父亲在他教生物化学的大学小实验室里，做出了千禧年最重大的发现。
When I saw him again, I vowed to discover the whereabouts of my father, and consequently joined the Indian Intelligence Bureau.
当我再次见到他时，我发誓要查明我父亲的下落，于是加入了印度情报局。
What does that have to do with those men shooting at us? And most importantly, why did you lie to me?
这跟那些朝我们开枪的人有什么关系？最重要的是，你为什么对我撒谎？
I'm sorry. I wasn't supposed to meet you, I wasn't supposed to fall in love with you.
对不起。我本不该遇见你，本不该爱上你。
But you have to believe me when I tell you that what I feel for you is real.
但你必须相信我，我对你的感情是真实的。
I can't believe this. Why are all these things happening to me? I can't take it anymore. Let me out of the car.
我简直不敢相信。为什么这些事都发生在我身上？我受不了了。让我下车。
Veronica, wait!
维罗妮卡，等等！
Okay, great. So now we're getting close to the end of this series. So what's gonna happen? Maybe Veronica is also a spy.
好的，太好了。现在我们快接近这个系列的结尾了。接下来会发生什么？也许维罗妮卡也是个间谍。
Oh my God, I don't think I can handle that.
天哪，我觉得我受不了这个。
Alright, so we really need your suggestions, we need your ideas. We want to know how you think the series ends or how you would want it to end.
好了，我们真的需要你们的建议，需要你们的想法。我们想知道你们认为这个系列如何结束，或者你们希望它如何结束。
Do you want it to be a happy ending?
你们希望是圆满结局吗？
Or a tragedy?
还是悲剧？
Or maybe action-filled ending?
或者充满动作的结局？
Alright, well, we've got two lessons left in this series, so visit our website at EnglishPod.com and leave your suggestions.
好了，这个系列还有两节课，所以请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，留下你们的建议。
Alright guys, we'll see you guys there and until next time.
好了，各位，我们那里见，下次再见。
Goodbye!
再见！
Bye!
拜拜！